STUDENT COUNCIL OFFICE
Our first sports day since
going co-ed is coming up.
Let's make sure all committees work
together to make this a smooth process.
Check the documents I've shared
with you for details.
Uh, Vice President Uzuki?
Why is your selfie among these documents?
No! I messed up!
I have one, too.
This is embarrassing,
so please just put them away.
I'm so glad I joined the student council.
I'll be collecting those documents.
Vice President.
I want to discuss the gymnasium schedule.
Shinobu-chan, help me with homework.
Uzuki-san, we have
a meeting for sports day.
Right. So, I think...
Vice President Uzuki's
always surrounded by people.
Are you surprised?
She's pretty, smart, and most of all...
Her voice is as lovely as ever.
Sorry, Shinobu-chan!
There were apparently some errors
in the sports day application.
Now we have to rewrite it.
But we can't tell what's wrong with it.
Leave it to me.
I'll fix it up.
That's our Shinobu-chan!
Great. I'm gonna be stuck here till dark.
Why do I always act like I can do it all?
Things are going to get hectic here, too.
PREPARING FOR SPORTS DAY
It's that time of year again.
Sports day is coming up.
We'll provide commentary, score updates,
and emcee announcements on the day.
We'll also handle all setup
of the audio equipment.
In a way, the broadcasting club
will be the stars behind the scenes.
The stars, huh?
That gets my blood pumping.
You'll be setting
the equipment up, errand boy.
We'll need a point
of contact for the clubs.
Oh, I'll do that.
I'm on the student council,
so that'll make it easier.
We'll also need a script and schedule
for the emcee announcements.
Who's going to do this?
Iko and I did that last year.
We messed up and left the table tennis
team without any commentary.
<JOBS FOR SPORTS DAY>
I'll do that, too.
Next, we'll need a scorer.
I can't do math!
Same.
I-I can do that, too.
Are you sure, Shinobu?
Isn't that too much work?
We can't ask you to do everything.
No problem. Just leave it all to me.
May I say something?
Why don't we put on an event of our own?
Something that's very broadcasting-like.
That sounds great. What should we do?
Well...
Let's do a maid café.
Casting a very broad net there,
but not broadcasting.
Announce the time?
Too basic!
Maybe rent out the clubroom
as storage space?
Quit trying to run a business.
How about reciting the
Yamabuki family's glorious history?
I'm sure there's a law out there
banning sleep-inducing broadcasts.
Uzuki.
Don't you have any ideas?
Nope. I'll just put all your ideas
together and make a pitch deck.
Okay, everyone try to come up
with ideas by tomorrow.
Okay.
Now, what say we go to karaoke?
I'm down!
Oh, sorry. I still have work to do.
Do you need help?
I'll be fine.
I can handle this much myself.
Yeah? See you, then.
Yep, bye-bye.
Bye-bye!
I made a list of songs I wanna sing.
For real?
I went and acted
like I can do it all again...
Whoa!
Wh-What's the matter, Yamabuki-kun?
Wait, what?
That's scary!
Seriously, what's going on?
Come with me, Uzuki.
Listen.
Do you swear you won't tell
a soul what I'm about to do?
I-I-I do!
What? Where's this coming from?
If he wants to keep it secret,
does that mean...
ADDITIVE-FREE COUGH DROP
What's that?
A cough drop.
Your voice sounds off today.
Take it. Maybe you'll feel better.
However!
Nobody can know that
I brought cough drops to school!
They're counted as snacks,
and yours truly cannot be known
for breaking school rules!
Her voice is as lovely as ever.
That's so sweet.
Thanks.
I'm surprised that you
could tell I sound different.
But of course. I'm always watching you
and listening to your voice.
It's my duty as the club's leader...
What's the matter?
O-Oh, you're always watching me?
Then I guess...
I should take better care
of my appearance.
Uzuki.
You seem to be biting off
more than you can chew.
This is just how I've always been.
I want to play a model student—
everybody's trusted vice president.
I guess I want to hear everyone tell me
how amazing and cool I am.
Wait, what am I even saying?
Sorry, forget you heard that.
I see. So you want
to bask in the spotlight.
Hey, don't put it like that.
Sure enough.
A smart, beautiful vice president
who wants to be an anchor.
That is a lot of prestige.
Everyone constantly has
high expectations of you,
so it comes with a lot of pressure.
But you can rejoice,
because that ends today.
After all, a being far more
"amazing and cool" than yourself—
yes, indeed—
yours truly is here now.
Everyone will be putting their
expectations on me instead.
I'm sorry to say that the spotlight
shall shine on me alone!
So, Uzuki.
Don't try to live up
to everyone's hopes all the time.
Rely on others more.
Actually, rely on me.
There is nobody more capable.
You're too much of a goody-two-shoes.
How about you try unwinding
every now and then?
Fine.
Yamabuki-kun.
Why don't you and I unwind right now?
ALL ALONE WITH YOU UNTIL DARK
LIBRARY
Just do it.
Close your eyes, and don't
open them until I tell you.
You'd better not to be trying
to do anything weird.
I won't.
I'm just unwinding.
Unwinding how?
Oh.
Alarm, alarm!
Uzuki! Did you just try
to feed me chocolate?!
Busted.
This is how I unwind.
Snacking in secret while doing
student council work is what I live for.
Okay...
but that's a lot.
What if someone finds out?
Right. I'll be in big trouble
if anyone finds out.
So snack with me
and be my partner in crime.
They're yummy, you know? Come on.
Stop.
Say ahh...
Wow! You look like a dog that
hates getting his teeth brushed!
Us Yamabukis stick to the rules.
Says the guy who brought cough drops.
You don't need to do this.
I won't rat you out.
Why'd we even come to the library, though?
Oh, I took on some work.
I'll need to use the copy machine.
I see. That's a lot.
Give me two-thirds of it.
STUDENT COUNCIL
FOR SPORTS DAY
Doing this alone would take until dark...
for an ordinary person.
Yours truly, however,
can make light work of it.
Let's get this over with and go home.
I know you're feeling under the weather.
Thanks, Yamabuki-kun.
You're so dependable.
Naturally.
I know I said you should rely on others,
but you're also too passive.
You should speak your mind more often,
at least with the broadcasting club.
I'm fine with the supporting role.
Like these little pieces of chocolate.
Even among snacks,
there are stars and supporting roles.
I'm the latter.
Those three are amazing.
They shine bright, and they want to fight
in a world where talent is everything.
I want to help them shine even brighter.
That's why I'd rather put
their priorities first.
And they're so quirky that someone has
to be the glue to bring them together.
That I get.
Right?
Last year's sports day
was a dumpster fire.
Nene-chan read names wrong on commentary.
Dekakari-san's so fast!
That's Oogari! "O-o-gari!"
Iko-chan broke the equipment.
And Rikka-chan couldn't come
because she caught a cold.
SORRY, I'M RUNNING A TEMPERATURE
ARE YOU OKAY? REST UP TODAY.
Those girls are hopeless!
I want to make sure
everything works out this year.
Especially since...
I'll probably leave the club in the fall.
What? You'll quit the club?!
Why? Are you transferring out?
Nah. I just want to focus on my studies.
My grades are pretty decent,
but I'll need to do better
to get into a good college.
The anchors on flagship stations
are all graduates from
prestigious colleges, right?
They also have good language skills
or other talents to make them stand apart.
I'm just a regular girl, so I'll have
to start hitting the books soon.
I get it.
You want to make some good memories
before you quit club for exam prep,
so you'll stick to a backup role,
help the other three shine bright,
and make sure this year's
sports day is a hit?
Pathetic!
I didn't raise you to be such a wimp!
Since when are you my dad?
Why don't you try to make
all your wishes come true?
Why not stay in the club, do what
you want to do for sports day,
and make some better memories that way?
Huh? But...
They say a bird in the hand
is better than two in the bush.
Uzuki...
Who do you think the man before you is?
Errand boy.
You all remember that title, huh?
Never forget that you have
yours truly on your side.
You're worried about your studies?
I'll tutor you.
You can't speak your mind?
I'll stand by you and back you up.
Anyone who chases two birds
but catches neither
is either a fool or alone.
And you aren't either of those.
Why are you willing to do so much for me?
I said I'd turn you all
into professionals.
I can't go losing you now.
Huh? Th-That came out of nowhere.
Also, you seem to have the wrong idea,
but you shine brightly yourself.
Just as brightly as the others.
Th-That's not true...
Do you mean to doubt yours truly?
I'm burning up.
Hearing you say that makes me
feel so warm and fuzzy inside.
Do you mean it?
Do you think I'm good enough
to stand alongside them?
Yes.
Okay.
You actually have something you
want to do for sports day, right?
You see everything through, huh?
I have an idea I want to try out.
Present it to the club.
I'll write a script.
Th-Thanks.
A-Also, uh...
Can you keep this between us?
The fact that you've
been snacking in secret?
Not that.
How I have an inferiority complex,
how I thought about leaving the club,
or how I'm having you help me.
Please?
Huh?
Hey, wait...
We're partners in crime now.
You keep your mouth shut, too.
You've got chocolate all over.
This is pretty good.
I like it.
BROADCASTING ROOM (TEMP)
There you have it.
BROADCASTING CLUB - CONFESSION
PROXY CONFESSION SERVICE
I'd like us to do this on sports day.
I call it the proxy confession service.
What do you say?
I-I know it'll be a lot of work,
so feel free to say no.
Hey, that sounds super fun!
It's very innovative.
I love the idea.
Let's do it!
R-Really?
What was a string phone, again?
It'd be a pain if our advisor
found out, though.
It's just the kind of thing she hates.
PARTNERS IN CRIME
RED TEAM - WHITE TEAM
Wow!
You're kidding me.
Why's he faster than
the guys on the sports teams?
Yamabuki-kun has finished
first in the race!
The man is blessed
with legs as swift as the wind!
Now he's doing commentary for himself!
Sorry I'm late!
Took you long enough!
How are there so many things to do?!
Get used to it! The five of us are
handling commentary for every competition!
The basketball match between
Classes 1-A and 1-D will begin soon.
Players, assemble in the gym at once.
Phew. That's done.
Rikka, we're in the scavenger hunt next.
Who's commentating?
Uh, I think it's...
Bear witness! This battle will
change the course of history!
And I, Yamabuki Arisu, am here to
kick it off with my bombastic voice!
Now, let me hear your piercing war cries!
Damn, he's loud.
I'm getting second-hand embarrassment.
What will these girls
have to find and borrow?
PERSON YOU RELY ON MOST
PERSON WHOSE VOICE YOU LIKE THE MOST
It won't be recorded
on the balance sheets!
This battle is sure to make
all tax accountants cry!
Come with me!
And me!
Uh, I need to commentate.
Just come!
Why Yamabuki?!
I'm so jelly!
I'm surprised there's
so much demand for me.
What were your prompts?
We're dead last! Step on it!
Uh, that's not happening
with the three of us holding hands.
But they said we have to
maintain contact the whole time.
This will mean helping the enemy team,
but yours truly hates
the taste of defeat even more.
Hey!
All they said was to
maintain contact, right?
Rawr!
Oi, is that even allowed?!
How is he still so fast?!
Curses!
Who gets so upset about second place?
What was written on your slip, Rikka?
Not telling you.
You hyper meanie!
Let me see!
Once you let me see yours.
Don't wanna.
Huh? Where's Yamabuki-kun?
Next up is the cavalry battle!
Yamabuki-kun,
two of the bases got injured.
What?
It's too bad.
We'll have to sit this one out.
Nonsense.
Yamabukis never go down without a fight.
Huh?
Next, we have the
second-year cavalry battle.
Hey! Why am I part of the horse?!
Blame yourself for gaining
three kilos in a month, Nene!
Whoa! What are you two doing?!
Yamabuki, what are you thinking?!
Holy cow!
Hey, Yamabuki-kun, we can't do this!
I am the Red Hare, and you are Lu Bu.
Listen to me!
Be careful not to get hurt
and, uh... good luck, I guess.
Get your face outta my face!
This is how a cavalry battle works!
Then look away!
But why?
Because you're so close,
it's bringing back memories!
Of what?
What? Obviously...
the k-ki...
ki-ki...
They got me.
Curses!
S-Sorry. Do you have to get so upset?
On to the next one, Nene.
Oh, r-right.
I couldn't fully become a horse.
I'm glad you didn't.
Is it just me, or have
those two grown closer lately?
Ew, why do I even care? Cringe!
It's none of my business!
Gah!
Damn it, Nene! Run!
We'll now take a fifteen-minute break.
Please be sure to rehydrate.
How I needed this break!
Everything's going well so far.
But this is where it gets real.
Right. We need to prep
for the lunchtime broadcast.
It'll be a lovely event.
A proxy confession service, huh?
BROADCASTING ROOM (TEMP) | CONFESSION
We set a string phone by the door for
students who want to confess something.
Our club will listen to their confession
BROADCASTING ROOM (TEMP)
and broadcast it to the whole school
while keeping it anonymous.
Although, we could have
just used anonymous letters.
That wouldn't do.
We have to listen to their voices
to maintain the spirit and emotion.
Ta-da!
PROXY CONFESSION SERVICE
I made flyers we can distribute
to students to promote the event.
Wouldn't a schoolwide
announcement work just as well?
But that'd tip the teachers off.
You know our school technically
doesn't allow relationships.
So we'll have to spring it on them?
But won't they try to stop us either way?
Not when the students
are having a ball, they won't.
Besides...
I'm the vice president
of the student council.
I'm the very picture of a model student!
You're saying they'll overlook it for you?
How optimistic you are, vice president.
I've always wanted to give it a shot...
Get the whole crowd
involved in a big event.
One I planned and led,
and one that'd be a great memory
for the broadcasting club.
Right.
First, let's hand out those flyers
without the teachers finding out.
What is this you don't want
the teachers finding out about?
Huh? L...
Lemon-chan!
BROADCASTING CLUB ADVISOR
ANDO LEMON (27)
I told you, stop calling me that.
THE ADVISOR'S CALLED LEMON-CHAN
Translation:
Timing:
Editing:
Sriram Gurunathan
Mariana Martinez
William Haggard
Quality Check:
Translation Check:
S Bilyeu
Michelle Tymon